<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ian L. Dolganov</title>
    <link>https://jexari.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jexari.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ian L. Dolganov</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jexari.github.io/media/icon_hu8079827bf8ba6556542529f13902f8f8_5736_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Ian L. Dolganov</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page elements&lt;/a&gt; such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The spaghetti code and how to avoid it</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/post/spaghetti_code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 14:42:51 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/post/spaghetti_code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none  &#34; open=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34; class=&#34;nav flex-column&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#introduction&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#temp&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; Definition of &#34;spaghetti code&#34;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#problems&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; Problems Caused by Spaghetti Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#solution&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; How to Avoid Spaghetti Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;introduction&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;. Introduction&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Programming is a creative process that encompasses many aspects, including the design, implementation, and maintenance of software. An important part of this process is writing clean, structured, and maintainable code. However, depending on the complexity of the project and the level of experience of the developer, the code can become confusing and difficult to understand. This code state is often referred to as &#34;spaghetti code&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;&#34;Spaghetti code&#34; is a term that is used in the programming field to refer to code that is complex in structure, disorganized, and difficult to maintain and understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;In this article, we will dive into a detailed study of the &#34;spaghetti code&#34; problem. We&#39;ll start by defining the term, discuss the problems that &#34;spaghetti code&#34; can cause, and look at ways to avoid and fix this problem. This article is for both experienced programmers who want to improve their coding skills and practices, and beginners who want to avoid common programming mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;temp&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;. Definition of &#34;spaghetti code&#34;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;As already mentioned, spaghetti code is code that is difficult to understand, change and maintain. There are a number of specific characteristics that are often associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Complex and confusing structure: Spaghetti code is often characterized by a lack of a clear and consistent structure. Code can &#34;jump&#34; from one part of the program to another, creating a confusing flow of execution. This structure makes it hard to understand how the code works and makes it hard to debug and change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Tightly related and interdependent components: In spaghetti code, different parts of the code are often closely related and interdependent. This means that changing one part of the code can affect other parts of the program. It also makes it difficult to test the code, since changes in one part of the code can have unexpected consequences in other parts of the program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Difficulty to make changes: Due to the tightly coupled components and the lack of structure, spaghetti code is usually difficult to change. Developers can take a long time to understand how the code works before they can make any changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Lack of documentation: Spaghetti code is often accompanied by little or no documentation, making it even more difficult to understand how it works. It also makes it difficult to share code with other developers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Scalability issues: Due to the complexity of the structure and the tight coupling of components, spaghetti code is usually difficult to scale. Adding new features or extending existing ones can be a complex and time-consuming task.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;All of these characteristics make spaghetti code problematic both for the developers who work on the code and for the organizations that maintain and use the software being developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;problems&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;. Problems Caused by Spaghetti Code&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Debugging and Support&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;One of the main problems with spaghetti code is the difficulty of debugging and maintaining it. Due to the lack of a clear structure and non-linear flow of execution, identifying and eliminating errors becomes much more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Performance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Spaghetti code can have a negative impact on program performance. Suboptimal algorithms and excessive complexity lead to computation of program execution time and resource usage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Increasing project costs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;The consequence of the above problems is an increase in project costs. Making changes to spaghetti code takes more time, leading to higher development and support costs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;solution&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;. How to Avoid Spaghetti Code&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;SOLID principles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;The SOLID principles are fundamental design principles for object-oriented programming that were formulated and summarized by Robert Martin. These principles are valued for helping to create cleaner, more modular, and maintainable code, making it more scalable and flexible. Following these principles can help you avoid creating spaghetti code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Single Responsibility Principle (SRP): According to this principle, each class or module in a program should have only one responsibility. This makes the code easier to understand and change, since changes in one part of the system are less likely to affect other parts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Open-Closed Principle (OCP): This principle states that software entities (classes, modules, functions, etc.) should be open for extension but closed for modification. This means that new features should be added through the creation of new code, rather than changing existing ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Liskov Substitution Principle (LSP): According to this principle, objects in a program should be replaceable with instances of their subtypes without changing the correctness of the program. This highlights the importance of honoring the contracts and obligations defined in the base types.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Interface Segregation Principle (ISP): This principle states that clients should not depend on interfaces they do not use. This means that large, &#34;fat&#34; interfaces should be broken down into smaller, more specific interfaces so that clients only have the dependencies they really need.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Dependency Inversion Principle (DIP): According to this principle, dependencies on concrete implementations should be replaced with dependencies on abstractions. This contributes to the flexibility and versatility of the code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Following these principles allows developers to create more organized and maintainable code, reducing the likelihood of spaghetti code. It takes some experience and understanding, but in the long run it makes the project easier to work with and maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Refactoring&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Refactoring is the process of changing the internal structure of a program or code to improve its readability, maintainability, extensibility, performance, and/or bug fixes, without changing the external behavior of the program. Regular code refactoring is also a key element in the fight against spaghetti code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Using Tests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Software testing allows you to check the correct operation of the code and identify errors. The use of tests also simplifies the process of refactoring and modifying the code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Design patterns&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Design patterns are repeatable solutions to common problems in software design. They are specific patterns or architectural approaches that help developers build systems that are flexible, maintainable, and extensible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;conclusion&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;. Conclusion&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Spaghetti code is a serious problem that can negatively impact software development and support. But by applying SOLID principles, regular refactoring, using tests and design patterns, you can significantly reduce the likelihood of spaghetti code and simplify the software development process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Li-Fi technology</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/post/li-fi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 14:42:51 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/post/li-fi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none  &#34; open=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34; class=&#34;nav flex-column&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#introduction&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#history_of_li-fi&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; History of Li-Fi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#wi-fi_or_li-fi&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; Wi-Fi or Li-Fi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#other_technologies_and_li-fi&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; Other wireless technologies and Li-Fi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;introduction&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;. Introduction&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Li-Fi is a bidirectional high—speed wireless technology that uses light waves to transfer data between devices. It is based on LEDs that can quickly turn on and off, forming bit sequences. Li-Fi refers to Visible light communication (VLC) technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;history_of_li-fi&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;. History of Li-Fi&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;The pioneer in the use of the term Li-Fi is Harald Haas. He delivered it during a TED Global talk in 2011. Harald Haas is also the co-founder of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purelifi.com/&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pureLiFi&lt;/a&gt;. The VLC technology itself, which I mentioned above, was shown to the world in 2012. In 2018, Li-Fi technology was tested at the BMW plant in Germany. At the moment, Li-Fi is under development, and not all devices can work with this technology. However, many companies are already interested in promoting Li-Fi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;wi-fi_or_li-fi&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;. Wi-Fi or Li-Fi&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;In comparison with Wi-Fi, Li-Fi transmits data at a higher speed, since the transmission speed is limited by the speed of switching on and off the LEDs. Thus, Li-Fi can reach speeds of up to 224 Gbps, which is several times faster than the bandwidth of the Wi-Fi standard. A more secure connection is also an advantage. Li-Fi does not penetrate walls, which makes data transmission more secure from interception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;But this technology also has disadvantages. For example, the coverage distance is less than 10 meters, while Wi-Fi has about 32 meters. In addition, constantly flashing LEDs can cause eye strain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;other_technologies_and_li-fi&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;. Other wireless technologies and Li-Fi&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Already, wireless technologies such as 5G and Wi-Fi 6 can compete for Li-Fi. They have a similar data transfer rate and operate over long distances in a wide frequency range. Nevertheless, for example, it is preferable to use Li-Fi for medical equipment, because the security is still higher for VLC connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;conclusion&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;. Conclusion&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Despite all the limitations, Li-Fi has a wide range of applications and can be used in production, hospitals, schools, transport, homes, restaurants, hotels. This technology may soon improve the quality of data transmission and communication in general, and will undoubtedly attract more and more attention in the near future. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of video game genres</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/post/game_genres/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 20:55:47 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/post/game_genres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Game genres:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Platformer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shooter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arena shooter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scroll shooter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3D shooter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rail shooter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fighting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beat ’em up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rhythm games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survival&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stealth action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simulator
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flight simulator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Car simulator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space simulator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Life simulator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Political simulator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other simulators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adventure
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text adventure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphic adventure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Сhoose your own adventure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual novel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive cinema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3D real time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategy
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4X&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real time strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wargame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Economic strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other strategies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Puzzle&lt;/li&gt;	
&lt;li&gt;Role-playing Games
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action-RPG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MMORPG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roguelike&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tactical RPG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open world RPG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JRPG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First Person Party RPGs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gacha games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mixed genres&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monetization in games</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/post/monetization_of_games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 20:38:19 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/post/monetization_of_games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none  &#34; open=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34; class=&#34;nav flex-column&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#introduction&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#methods_of_monetization&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; Methods of monetization&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#inapp_purchases&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; In-app purchases &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#advertising&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; Advertising&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#subscription&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; Subscription system&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#preorder&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; Pre-order and crowdfunding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#marketplaces&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; Marketplaces &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#premium_games&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; Premium games &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#types_of_players&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; Types of players&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#social_proof&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; Social proof &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#choice_paralysis&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; Choice paralysis &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;introduction&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. Introduction&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Game development has always been a rather time-consuming and expensive process. In our world, enthusiasm can infect a team only at the initial stage of the project (and even then not always), then financial injections into the project will be needed. Here we are faced with monetization. Monetization is a type of process that a video game publisher can use to generate revenue from a video game product. Its competent study will allow not only to recoup the invested funds, but also to profit from the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;1.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;The pattern in the picture above is quite simple, you release a game, then pay for it and get some income that you invest in the company and prepare a new game. This is the cycle without which the work of any project is impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;methods_of_monetization&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2. Methods of monetization&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Here we come to the issue of making money on video games. Mankind has come up with many ways to make money on the development of dopamine in players. One of the first can be considered a fee for arcade machines. Quite a lot of time has passed since then, gaming halls are a thing of the past and almost every home has its own computer or other device that can run games. The methods of monetization have also evolved, here are the main ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p id=&#39;inapp_purchases&#39;&gt;In-app purchases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Usually, when using this type, the in-game store has additional products that the user buys at will.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p id=&#39;advertising&#39;&gt;Advertising&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;The most obvious form of monetization is in-game advertising. This is a great way to make money, but it&#39;s worth noting that users who pay money expect ad-free access. There are several main types of advertising content in games: banner ads (a static banner in part of the screen), full-screen ads (text-graphic ads that cover the background of the game), video ads, game ads (a mini-game in which you can perform primitive actions).&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;What to choose? It primarily depends on the type of game. For example, in shooters, it is better to forego full-screen ads and banner ads and choose video ads that will open between game sessions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p id=&#39;subscription&#39;&gt;Subscription system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;The user pays a certain amount once a month / year and gets access to the game for this period. Works well with trial access to the game. During this time, the user will feel the possibilities of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Pros: profit is predictable and stable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Cons: it is necessary to constantly maintain and update the content, to maintain its uniqueness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p id=&#39;preorder&#39;&gt;Pre-order and crowdfunding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;If developers make games for fun, then you can support them through voluntary donations. As a result, we get a product that has no ads, no micropayments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p id=&#39;marketplaces&#39;&gt;Marketplaces&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Typically, income comes as a percentage of sales of in-game items between users. Works great if the audience of the game is large and the game has a lot of things to exchange.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p id=&#39;premium_games&#39;&gt;Premium games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Perhaps the oldest type of monetization, but still quite popular. The scheme is simple: the user pays money and receives the product. This type is most often used by large brands, as their name guarantees quality. Sooner or later, a successful paid game will be copied and released for a more affordable price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Sometimes these games may also combine additional in-game purchases or payment for separate content that is not included in the price of the game itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;types_of_players&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;3. Types of players&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;If the user can deposit money in the game, then it will be useful for us to get acquainted with the types of such payers. Traditionally, there are 3 types of players according to the size of donations: fry or minnows (pay small amounts), dolphins (pay more) and whales (pay huge amounts). In 2015, there was a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gamesindustry.biz/its-all-about-the-players&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; on this topic. It was revealed that half of all donators are fry, 40% are dolphins, and 10% are whales. And here we see that these 10% of whales provide 80% of all income. And that half of the fry at the exit gives 1% of the total profit. From this we can conclude that our task is to use our tools to make fry into dolphins, dolphins into whales, and keep the whales, because in fact it is the whales that generate income from the game.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;3.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Distribution of users by groups&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;4.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Percentage of income from each group&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;social_proof&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;4. Social proof&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Social proof is one of the triggers in marketing that encourages the player to make purchases based on the opinions of others. One example of this technique can be called reviews about the game. It is more pleasant for the user to see when choosing a game not 4, but 5 stars. Or, for example, a notification about the purchase of in-game content by someone. It is not necessary that users know each other, they can be in the same clan or even just in the general chat of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;choice_paralysis&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;5. Choice paralysis&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Choice paralysis is the inability of a person to choose one offer from many. That is, if there are 25 products in the game store, then it will be more difficult for the user to choose something than when choosing from 5. Why is this happening? The point is that the player feels the risk of losing something. After all, he wants to choose the best at the moment. And in these conditions, many prefer to abandon the choice altogether. This should be taken into account when developing an in-game store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;conclusion&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;6. Conclusion&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Competent monetization can not only pay off the project, but also bring significant income to your company. It is important to carefully study the market before the final choice of how to make a profit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pattern recognition</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/post/recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 18:14:49 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/post/recognition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none  &#34; open=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34; class=&#34;nav flex-column&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#problem&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; Task Formulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#solution&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; The solution of the problem &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;problem&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;. Task Formulation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;The program describes 3 classes, each of which is represented by 3 objects. Other objects written in arrays are given as input. It is necessary to recognize which element is displayed in the input arrays to which element the distance is closer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;solution&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;. The solution of the problem&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;For a Python solution, you can visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Jexari/intelligent-systems&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15 Puzzle</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/post/tags_game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 13:08:49 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/post/tags_game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none  &#34; open=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34; class=&#34;nav flex-column&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#игра_в_15&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; 15 puzzle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#формулировка_задачи_15&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; The mathematics of permutations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#формулировка_задачи_15&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; Task Formulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#решение_задачи_15&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; The solution of the problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;игра_в_15&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;. 15 puzzle&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;In 1878, Noah Chapman invented the game of 15 puzzle. The puzzle consists of 15 identical square tiles in a square box. Each such element is numbered. The box has a size of 4x4 tiles (1 square remains empty). There may also be other variations of this game 3x3, 5x5 and others. The goal of the game is simple - arrange the tiles in ascending order by moving them inside the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;математика_перестановок&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;. The mathematics of permutations&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;The number of possible initial positions of the game is n!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
    .heatMap {
        text-align: center;
    }
    .heatMap th {
        background: grey;
        word-wrap: break-word;
        text-align: center;
    }
    td, th {
    	border: 1px solid black;
    }
    .heatMap td:nth-child(1) { background: #98FB98; }
    .heatMap td:nth-child(2) { background: #B0E0E6; }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;heatMap&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Size&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;The number of initial positions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;2x2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;2x4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;40 320&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;3x3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;362 880&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;In exactly half of all possible initial positions of the 15 puzzle, it is impossible to bring them to an assembled form. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mathworld.wolfram.com/15Puzzle.html&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read more here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;формулировка_задачи_15&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;. Task Formulation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Given 2 matrices: initial and final. Implement a solution to the problem (performing &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Depth-first_search&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a depth-first search&lt;/a&gt;), applying &lt;a href=&#34;https://ru.wikipedia.org/wiki/Эвристический_алгоритм&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;heuristic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;решение_задачи_15&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;. The solution of the problem&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
For a Python solution, you can visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Jexari/intelligent-systems&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my repository&lt;/a&gt;. 
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaufmann&#39;s NK-automaton</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/post/the_kaufmann_automaton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 23:11:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/post/the_kaufmann_automaton/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none  &#34; open=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34; class=&#34;nav flex-column&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#about_the_kaufmann_automaton&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; What is a Kaufmann&#39;s automaton and how does it work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#problem&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; The task formulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#solution&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; The solution of the problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;about_the_kaufmann_automaton&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;. What is a Kaufmann&#39;s automaton and how does it work?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;The NK-automaton is a network of N Boolean logical elements. Each logic element has K inputs and one output. The signals at the inputs and outputs of the elements are binary (they take the values 0 or 1). The outputs of some elements go to the inputs of others, these connections are absolutely random, but the number of inputs K of each element is static. The logical elements are also chosen randomly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Automaton are autonomous (there are no external inputs). The number of logical elements included in the automaton is assumed to be large, N&gt;1. The automaton functions in discrete time: t = 1,2,3,… The state of the automaton at each moment of time t is determined by the vector X(t) – the totality of the output signals of all logic elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;In the process of functioning, the sequence of states converges to an attractor - a limit cycle. The sequence of states X(t) in this attractor can be considered as a “program” for the functioning of the automaton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;The number of attractors M and the typical attractor length L are important characteristics of NK-automaton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;problem&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;. The task formulation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Input:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;set n=4, к=2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;set initial vector (e.g. int v0[] = {1, 1, 0, 1, 0, 0})
&lt;li&gt;set a matrix of connections, for example:
&lt;p&gt;int n[1] = {0, 1, 0, 1, 0, 0};&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;int n[2] = {1, 0, 1, 0, 0, 0};&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;int n[3] = {0, 1, 0, 1, 0, 0};&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;int n[4] = {1, 0, 0, 0, 0, 1};&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;int n[5] = {0, 0, 0, 0, 1, 1};&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;int n[6] = {0, 0, 1, 0, 1, 0}; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is also necessary to describe the logical elements.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;number of different attractors.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;solution&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;. The solution of the problem&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
For a Python solution, you can visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Jexari/intelligent-systems&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my repository&lt;/a&gt;. 
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dictionaries in Python</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/post/dictionaries_in_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 22:21:10 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/post/dictionaries_in_python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;In this entry, we will talk about such a data type as a dictionary. What it is? A dictionary is a data structure in which information is stored in a key-value format. Here I will explain how to access the information stored in a dictionary and how to edit this information, talk about the main methods of dictionaries and how to use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Let&#39;s create 2 dictionaries, one stores information about students&#39; grades, the other contains a list of students who eat in the canteen (Fig. 1.1). The dictionary is written in curly brackets. It can either contain initial data (&lt;i&gt;students_marks&lt;/i&gt;) or be empty (&lt;i&gt;student_who_eat_in_dining_room&lt;/i&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;As mentioned earlier, all information in dictionaries is stored in the key-value format. If we need to get the value assigned to a particular key, we can do it directly or through the &lt;i&gt;get()&lt;/i&gt; method. If the key we entered is missing, then the &lt;i&gt;get()&lt;/i&gt; method will return &lt;i&gt;None&lt;/i&gt;, but the call without it will give an error. This is important to consider when creating projects where it is not known for sure whether a key with the same name exists in the dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;We can also add new keys and values, as well as change the values already in the dictionary. All the actions described above and their result can be seen in Fig. 1.1-1.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;1_1.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 1.1. Program listing 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;1_2.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 1.2. Program output 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Consider two other methods, namely &lt;i&gt;keys()&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;values()&lt;/i&gt;. The first returns us all the keys in the dictionary, the second returns all the values, such as &lt;i&gt;dict_keys&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;dict_values&lt;/i&gt; respectively. If we need to remove a pair from a dictionary, we can use &lt;i&gt;del&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;pop ()&lt;/i&gt;. To display all key-value pairs, you need the &lt;i&gt;items()&lt;/i&gt; method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;2_1.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 2.1. Program listing 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;2_2.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 2.2. Program output 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;To view these and other Python programs, you can visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Jexari/python_for_site&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft FrontPage</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/post/frontpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 17:47:07 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/post/frontpage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none  &#34; open=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34; class=&#34;nav flex-column&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#general_information&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; General information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#installation_frontpage&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; Installation Frontpage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#my_web_page&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; My Web page &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#outcome&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; Conclusion &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;general_information&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;. General information&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Web pages can be created in several ways - from scratch or based on some kind of template. Both of these approaches can be implemented in Microsoft FrontPage. This editor was one of the best of its time, allowing you to edit HTML code, as well as view all changes in direct view mode. This editor did not require knowledge of the basics of HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main features of the editor:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;create and save web pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;save web pages directly to the Web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;view and administer web pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create complex web page designs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use predefined HTML tags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use ready-made images from the software package, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;installation_frontpage&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;. Installation Frontpage&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Installation of the program is simple, available when installing Office 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;installation_frontpage.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Installation Microsoft FrontPage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;windows_menu_frontpage.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Microsoft FrontPage in Start Menu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;frontpage_prog.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Interface FrontPage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;my_web_page&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;. My Web page&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;I will not dwell on creating a web page in detail, since in fact we are working with the Microsoft Word interface. I will only show the final web page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;my_web_page.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;outcome&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;. Conclusion&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Obviously, it is impossible to create a site with a modern design on a program for Windows XP, but despite this, some sites written in FrontPage still work. The Microsoft Frontpage was replaced by Microsoft Expression Web and Microsoft SharePoint Designer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User management in Windows</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/post/user_management_windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 21:42:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/post/user_management_windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none  &#34; open=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34; class=&#34;nav flex-column&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#introduction&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#Управление-учетными-записями-через-lusrmgrmsc&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; Account management via lusrmgr.msc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#управление-учетными-записями-через-cmd&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; Account management via cmd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;introduction&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;. Introduction&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;An account is a set of data about a user that is necessary to authenticate him and provide access to his personal data and settings. Thus, an account consists of a username and password (or other means of authentication). The password is often encrypted or hashed. An account can store a user&#39;s photo or other image, take into account the age of various statistical characteristics of the user&#39;s behavior in the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;It is not uncommon for several users to work on the same computer. On Linux, it is more convenient to manage users on the command line. In the Microsoft family of operating systems, this feature is also present, as is the GUI (Graphical User Interface).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Account management is one of the primary responsibilities of a system administrator. It is very convenient to combine users into groups, edit their access rights depending, for example, on their position in the company. This directly affects the security of the information system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;Управление-учетными-записями-через-lusrmgrmsc&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;. Account management via lusrmgr.msc&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Immediately after installing Windows, we start working with Administrator rights. These rights in the OS allow, for example, to create, modify, delete other accounts, perform any operations to configure the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;The lusrmgr.msc snap-in is used to manage accounts (Fig. 1). We can also open it by entering the name in the &#34;Run&#34; command field, or in the internal system search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;lusrmgr.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 1. lusrmgr.msc window&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;In order to create an account, you need to do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to the &#34;Users&#34; folder (Fig. 2).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the menu bar, select &#34;Action&#34;, then &#34;New User&#34;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure to fill in the &#34;User&#34; field, the rest if necessary (Fig. 3).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;users_in_os.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 2. OS users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;user-creation.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 3. User creation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;A user group is a collection of user accounts that have the same rights and security permissions. The user account must be a member of at least one user group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Different users have different needs, the administrator can allocate the necessary permissions and prohibitions. If we have many users, then it is convenient to distribute rights not individually, but by user groups. Windows has several built-in groups: Administrators, Users, Power Users, Backup Operators, Guests, Remote Desktop Users, DHCP Administrators, DHCP Users, and WINS Users. We can also create our own group. For this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to the &#34;Groups&#34; folder (Fig. 4).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the menu bar, select &#34;Action&#34;, then &#34;Create Group&#34;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure to fill in the &#34;Group Name&#34; field, the rest if necessary (Fig. 5.1 - 5.2).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;list_os_all_users.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 4. List of all groups&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;groups_creation.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 5.1. Create a group&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;adding_a_user_to_a_group.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 5.2. Adding users to a group&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;You can view which groups a user belongs to in the Users folder by right-clicking on the user, then selecting Properties, Group Memberships. If we go to the &#34;General&#34; tab, we can manage the user&#39;s password, and also, if necessary, disable the account (Fig. 6).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;management_in_general.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 6. Management in the &#34;General&#34; tab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;The administrator can also set password time limits, for this you need to use the gpedit.msc snap-in. Next, go to &#34;Computer Configuration&#34;, &#34;Windows Configuration&#34;, &#34;Security Settings&#34;, &#34;Account Policy&#34;, &#34;Password Policy&#34; (Fig. 7).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;changing_the_password_expiration_time.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 7. Changing the password expiration time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;управление-учетными-записями-через-cmd&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;. Account management via cmd&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;As mentioned earlier, we can manage accounts through the command line. To begin with, we will write the command whoami and whoami /user (Fig. 8). The first displays information about the current user, the second additionally shows the SID (security identifier). SID is a variable length data structure that identifies a user, group, domain, or computer account. The last 4 digits indicate the object&#39;s relative security identifier (RID). 3 sets of numbers before RID is just the SID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;whoami_and_whoami_user.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 8. whoami and whoami /user&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;For further account management, we need the net user command. With it, we can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;add an account (net user NAME PASSWORD /ADD) (Fig. 9.1);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add account password (net user NAME PASSWORD) (Fig. 9.4);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rename account (wmic useraccount where name=&#39;NAME&#39; rename ‘NEWNAME’) (Fig. 9.2);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;view account information (net user NAME) (Fig. 9.3);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;change account password (net user NAME NEW_PASSWORD);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disable account (net user NAME /active:no);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;delete your account (net user NAME /delete) (Fig. 9.5).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;adding_an_account.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 9.1. Adding an account&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;adding_an_account_2.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 9.2. Adding an account&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;adding_an_account_3.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 9.3. Adding an account&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;adding_a_password_to_account.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 9.4. Adding a password to an account&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;middle&#34; src=&#34;delition_an_account.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;Figure. 9.5. Deleting an account&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;To work with groups, you must use the net localgroup command. For example, with it we can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;list all local groups (net localgroup);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add local group (net localgroup GROUPNAME /add);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add existing user accounts to a group (net localgroup GROUPNAME USERNAME1 USERNAME2 /add /domain);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;display a list of users in a local group (net localgroup GROUPNAME).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;conclusion&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;. Conclusion&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Thus, having become familiar with the basics of user management in the Windows operating system, we can draw the following conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Creating an account, changing the account password, and many other actions can be performed both through various snap-ins and through the command line. In the second case, we can use, for example, the net user command. Also with group changes, they can also be done in the two ways described above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;To ensure information security, it is necessary to sort their accounts into groups, where you can enter restrictions on their rights (for example, viewing certain folders).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Project</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/project/my-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 23:10:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/project/my-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Basics</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/post/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 18:44:49 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/post/git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none  &#34; open=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34; class=&#34;nav flex-column&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#about_git&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; What is Git and what is it for?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#main_commands&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; Basic commands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;nav-item&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#dictionary&#34; class=&#34;nav-link&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; Dictionary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;about_git&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;. What is Git and what is it for?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;What is &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34; target = &#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; for, and what is a version control system anyway? A version control system is a system that records changes to a file or set of files over time and allows you to revert to a specific version later. Simply put, in case of a file change, the file and the place of the change will be marked, you can also undo the previously entered file changes, see who last changed something and caused the problem and when, and much more. If you break something or lose files, you can easily fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;One such system is Git. At the moment, it is the most common for a number of reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Free and open source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple branching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Hostings are provided for git repositories, for example: GitHub, Codebase, Bitbucket, GitLab, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;main_commands&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;. Basic commands:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
    .heatMap {
        text-align: center;
    }
    .heatMap th {
        background: grey;
        word-wrap: break-word;
        text-align: center;
    }
    td, th {
    	border: 1px solid black;
    }
    .heatMap td:nth-child(1) { background: #437DD4; }
    .heatMap td:nth-child(2) { background: #FF4940; }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;heatMap&#34;&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Command&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Command description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git init&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;creating a new repository&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git status&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;view status of current files&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git add&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;adding changes and new files to the current directory&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git add file.py&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;adding file.py&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git .add&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;adding all changes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git commit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;creating a new commit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git commit -m &amp;rsquo;text&#39;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;creating a commit called text&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git branch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;shows a list of all branches&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git branch -v&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;shows a list of branches and the latest commit in each&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git branch name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;creates a new branch name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git branch -D name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;deletes a branch name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git checkout&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;switching between recent commits&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git checkout file&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;revert file to last commit state&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git config&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;configuration and options git&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git config &amp;ndash;global user.name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;shows username&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git config &amp;ndash;global user.name &amp;lsquo;New name&amp;rsquo;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;changes username&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git config &amp;ndash;global user.email&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;shows the user&amp;rsquo;s email&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git config &amp;ndash;global user.email &amp;rsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:name@gmail.com&#34;&gt;name@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&#39;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;changes the user&amp;rsquo;s email&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git push&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;uploading local commits to a remote repository&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git pull&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;downloads changes from the remote repository to the local one&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;git clone&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;cloning a project from a remote repository&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#39;dictionary&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;section-num&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;. Dictionary&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Branch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;A branch or copy of the project where you can make any changes, they will not affect the main project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Git&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;How files and their versions are stored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Cloning&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Copying a repository to a hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Commit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Set with changes (changed, new and added files) written to the local repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Push&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Sending changes to the server.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://owchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Eating...&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Only the speaker can read these notes
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Press &lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;`S`&lt;/span&gt; key to view
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  {{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/media/boards.jpg&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;#0000FF&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;my-style&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;navy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/discussions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Project</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis posuere tellus ac convallis placerat. Proin tincidunt magna sed ex sollicitudin condimentum. Sed ac faucibus dolor, scelerisque sollicitudin nisi. Cras purus urna, suscipit quis sapien eu, pulvinar tempor diam. Quisque risus orci, mollis id ante sit amet, gravida egestas nisl. Sed ac tempus magna. Proin in dui enim. Donec condimentum, sem id dapibus fringilla, tellus enim condimentum arcu, nec volutpat est felis vel metus. Vestibulum sit amet erat at nulla eleifend gravida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nullam vel molestie justo. Curabitur vitae efficitur leo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed pulvinar mauris dui, eget varius purus congue ac. Nulla euismod, lorem vel elementum dapibus, nunc justo porta mi, sed tempus est est vel tellus. Nam et enim eleifend, laoreet sem sit amet, elementum sem. Morbi ut leo congue, maximus velit ut, finibus arcu. In et libero cursus, rutrum risus non, molestie leo. Nullam congue quam et volutpat malesuada. Sed risus tortor, pulvinar et dictum nec, sodales non mi. Phasellus lacinia commodo laoreet. Nam mollis, erat in feugiat consectetur, purus eros egestas tellus, in auctor urna odio at nibh. Mauris imperdiet nisi ac magna convallis, at rhoncus ligula cursus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cras aliquam rhoncus ipsum, in hendrerit nunc mattis vitae. Duis vitae efficitur metus, ac tempus leo. Cras nec fringilla lacus. Quisque sit amet risus at ipsum pharetra commodo. Sed aliquam mauris at consequat eleifend. Praesent porta, augue sed viverra bibendum, neque ante euismod ante, in vehicula justo lorem ac eros. Suspendisse augue libero, venenatis eget tincidunt ut, malesuada at lorem. Donec vitae bibendum arcu. Aenean maximus nulla non pretium iaculis. Quisque imperdiet, nulla in pulvinar aliquet, velit quam ultrices quam, sit amet fringilla leo sem vel nunc. Mauris in lacinia lacus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a tincidunt lacus. Curabitur at urna sagittis, dictum ante sit amet, euismod magna. Sed rutrum massa id tortor commodo, vitae elementum turpis tempus. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean purus turpis, venenatis a ullamcorper nec, tincidunt et massa. Integer posuere quam rutrum arcu vehicula imperdiet. Mauris ullamcorper quam vitae purus congue, quis euismod magna eleifend. Vestibulum semper vel augue eget tincidunt. Fusce eget justo sodales, dapibus odio eu, ultrices lorem. Duis condimentum lorem id eros commodo, in facilisis mauris scelerisque. Morbi sed auctor leo. Nullam volutpat a lacus quis pharetra. Nulla congue rutrum magna a ornare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aliquam in turpis accumsan, malesuada nibh ut, hendrerit justo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Quisque sed erat nec justo posuere suscipit. Donec ut efficitur arcu, in malesuada neque. Nunc dignissim nisl massa, id vulputate nunc pretium nec. Quisque eget urna in risus suscipit ultricies. Pellentesque odio odio, tincidunt in eleifend sed, posuere a diam. Nam gravida nisl convallis semper elementum. Morbi vitae felis faucibus, vulputate orci placerat, aliquet nisi. Aliquam erat volutpat. Maecenas sagittis pulvinar purus, sed porta quam laoreet at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example conference paper</title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/publication/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/publication/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://jexari.github.io/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jexari.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
